

CHARLES OUVERLEAUX

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+4915739566054 charlesantoine.ouverleaux@gmail.com Berlin, Germany





TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Ruby on Rails
- Python and Django
- SQL (mySQL, PostgreSQL)
- APIs, JSON, scraping
- Javascript ES6
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Git, Github
- Excel/VBA

LANGUAGES

- French Native
- English Native
- Dutch Fluent, spoken
- German Conversational

INTERESTS

- Woodworking
- Surfing and travelling
- Concerts and music

"After working 6 years in sales and marketing I decided to focus on the parts of my jobs I enjoyed the most: **coding and problem solving**. Always eager to learn more, I changed career path and dived into programming. I wish to combine my analytical mindset and understanding of ecommerce to start my career as a developer."

EXPERIENCE

Strategic start up manager

Amazon | Berlin (2019 - 2021)

- Consulted Europe's largest startups and emerging brands (>\$20M), grow their businesses across 6 countries, generating a +200% YoY growth for a portfolio of +25 brands
- Co-ordinated a self-service online platform, scaling operations and education for > 500 brands, reducing operational queries by 50%
- Set-up a tool evaluating brands achievements and team resource allocations for +200 brands
- Owned advanced ETL/SQL queries for large data sets, delivering outputs for weekly and monthly business reviews
- Acted as Amazon Data Champion, improving data accessibility for the EU business teams

Head of CRM, marketing analyst

nu3 GmbH | Berlin (2017 - 2019)

- Optimised retention developing global strategies, customer journeys and campaigns across 6 markets
- Develop and maintain the marketing dashboard which hosted and managed all marketing optimization processes
- Implemented automated processes reducing manual efforts (-8H/week) and increasing content quality (no errors)

Category manager

nu3 GmbH | Berlin (2016 - 2017)

- Led the change of portfolio strategy from marketplace to an own brand shop, resulting in a +35% increase in profitability
- Identified, acquired and pushed the growth of offline cooperations, leading to the launch in shops like Di and COOP

International category manager

Home24 | Berlin (2014 - 2016)

• Launched and developed the sales of the Belgian shop

EDUCATION

Full-stack development

Le Wagon | Berlin (2021)

- 9 week coding bootcamp, ranked #1 worldwide
- Designed, implemented and shipped to production a clone of AirBnB and a rails prototype of www.surf-easy.com - A mobile first app that helps surfers find the best waves depending on their level, location and live weather data. It was developed as a team of 4 in 2 weeks

Bachelor & Master degree business engineering

ICHEC management school | Brussels (2008 - 2014)

- Finance and international management
- Graduated with honors
- Master erasmus: Europe-Universität Viadrina Frankfurt (Oder)
- Bachelor erasmus: Erasmus: InHolland University Amsterdam